Traders, in this video you're going to
understand the power of confluences.
Now, it's time for you to be organized
as a trader. Whatever you are doing on
the chart, you need to have a reason.
Don't just jump in because of pressure
or the market is moving. You want to
just flow with the market. Stay
organized. Map it out. Have specific
technical factors that you're looking
out for before you decide to click the
buy button or the sell button. We're
going to go to the chart and I will
break down the confluences I personally
use to trade and make good money like
pack out good funds out of the chart.
You know the drill. Let's go to the
chat. All right traders, let's get to
discover the power of confluences in
trading because most of you now take
trades without considering some factors
in the market. You don't just jump into
the market just because of the pressure
that you want to make money. You need to
stay very organized. Even when you're
mapping out your trading plan, you need
to have the list of technical factors
you need to see present on the chart
before you decide to take your trades.
That is what we call confluences. So a
quick one from the screen you can see
I've been able to give a simple meaning
of what confluence means. So it means
the combination of multiple technical
factors which helps to give out higher
probability setups. So now why does it
matter? I've also been able to map out
why conferences matter. Now it will
increase your accuracy in the market and
then it will also boost your confidence
and also reduce overtrading. Most
traders you know will drop a message for
me or will ask me questions how can I
overcome overtrading and the rest. When
you have what you are looking out for on
the chart, it's not possible that you
will see it all the time. It's not
possible that all your conferences will
keep appearing back to back. But when
you have specifically what you are
looking out for on the chart, you will
have to calm down and wait for that to
show up before you decide to trade. So
it will reduce that overtrading. But
when you are jumping in back to back,
that is when you see yourself you've
made profit. you'll give it back to the
market. You made profit again, you will
give it back to the market and then it
will also boost your confidence whenever
you want to trade. Now most people they
see a very probable setup but then they
will hesitate to place their trade. Why?
Because they don't even know whether the
market is going to go to their direction
or not. Although nothing is certain when
trading but then when your confences are
intact, the confidence will be there.
your confidence level will increase for
you to either click the buy button if
it's a bullish trend or the sell button
if it's a bearish trend and now it will
increase your accuracy. The list of
conferences you should have are you know
technical factors that you've tried out
and you've noticed that they work. So
all you just need to do is to be looking
out for them all the time whenever
you're looking at the chart. Just
patiently wait for them to show up
whenever you're looking at the chat. And
whenever they show up, don't hesitate.
Take your trades. So I want to quickly
show you guys my own combination, the
conferences I look out for whenever I
take trades. So whenever I want to take
trades, these are the conferences I look
out for. We can see I named it my
powerful conference combination.
So the first one here is my structural
bias, which we can also call market
structure. I need to understand where
the market is directed at. That is
number one. I need to have my structural
bias. The market must either be bullish
or bearish. I don't trend I don't trade
when the market is ranging. Whenever the
market is ranging, I don't trade. I will
wait for it to give me a particular
direction whether to the upside. If it's
moving to the upside, I am buying. If
it's moving to the downside, I am
selling. But if it's ranging, I'll stay
off until I get a direction from the
market. Now, when I get that structural
bias, the next thing I need to look out
for is the recent break of structure.
The recent break of structure following
my bias. That is why the structural bias
is number one. With this structural
bias, I will have a clue of the next
thing I need to do. Then I will just use
all these ones, back it up, and then
take my trades. So I need to look out
for the recent break structure from my
entry time frame which is 15 minutes.
And then once I get the reset break
structure I look out for where the break
structure you know emanated from. That
is the impulsive movement that caused
the breakoff structure where it started
from and from there that is where I will
map out my other block. Then once I map
out my order block, I also need to get
other technical factors that will make
my order block valid and they are what?
Liquidity and imbalance. So the other
block I am trying to take shares from
must create an imbalance. And then for
price to tap into my order block, it
must clear liquidity. So I'm going to
show you guys few examples of trades I
took that dished out massive funds for
me and how all these things were present
before I decided to take that trade. So
this is a beautiful setup that dished
out full TP for me. You can see how
beautiful this setup is. Now I did not
just see this on the chart and just
decided to take a buy. You can see I've
been able to break it down. So even from
my trading plan that is what I have
staying organized as a trader that is
what will help you nothing is certain
when trading nothing is certain and then
trading generally it's not easy trading
is not easy so you need to organize
yourself as a trader
have specific technical factors you need
to see before you take your trades for
me you can see what I have here the
structural bias
was bullish. This is a trade I took on
GBP JPY structural bias bullish recent
break structure. This is it. You can see
the recent breaker structure here. Now
the other block that cost the breaker
structure. You can see how I highlighted
it. I highlighted it. Now once I get
that my breaker structure, I am ready to
take dreads. Once I get that my record
structure and map out the origin that
caused that record structure which is my
other block. Then I am getting ready to
take trades other block mapped out. Now
I need to look for other conferences
that will make my order block what
valid. Now like I said my order block
candlestick should create an imbalance.
So you can see the imbalance here every
present. Now liquidity
present now you can see the liquidity
here. Liquidity is also present from
here. You can see price cleared
everything tapped in and it moved
straight to my direction. I am using all
these things because I've been able to
try them for years and it's working for
me. Dishing out massive funds for me. So
even if I'm sleeping, I'll wake me up my
conferences. These are the things I will
need to see on the chart before I take
my trades. Very simple and
straightforward. This is another
beautiful setup from XAU/USD that is
gold. Now you can see this particular
tread dished out massive funds for me.
So it was an entry here first and then I
was able to catch continuation entry
here. Still sticking to my strategy and
all the conferences I need to say. So
you can see here structural bias here
bullish B present. This is it block
present. When you map out the order
block, you look out for the imbalance
the order block created. Liquidity
present obviously. So you can see price
clearly tapped in moved to my direction.
This is also a continuation entry where
I had to like add positions. But you can
see we have break structure the
imbalance created market tapped in moved
to my direction. Now when you see setups
like this they would look very beautiful
but then I can wait for days for this to
show up on the chart. A lot of things
will be happening on the chart. I won't
react unless I see what I am looking out
for which is the list you have here. I
need to see all my confluences. That is
the power of confluences. It will help
you stay organized. Remember why it
matters. the accuracy, the confidence
and you staying organized generally. So
let me also show you guys another setup.
This was a quick sale from BTC USD. So
after getting this change of character
mapped out the origin that caused the
change of character, the FVG it created
and then the liquidity price clear. Now
you can see how price tapped in and then
straight to the downside. Now one thing
about this confluences that I look out
for is that whenever I see that I am not
going to hesitate guys I am not going to
hesitate. So whenever I see it, I am
taking my trades. As price is come, once
I see that, I'll just place my entry.
Aggressive entry from 15 minutes time
frame. Aggressive entry, I wait for
price to just come there, mitigate the
order I have there. And then if it's a
good one, it's going straight to my TP.
And if it's a bad one, it's going to SL.
And I will understand why it has gone to
SL and then reanalyze and still come
back on track. But then when you are
trading without any reason, if you make
money, you don't even know why you are
making money. And then if you make
losses, you don't even know why you made
losses. So you will just be so
disorganized in the market. And that
should not be you as a trader. You need
to understand yourself in the market.
You need to be sane when trading. You
don't just jump in like that. So make
sure you have your confluences intact. I
also have videos where I've been able to
explain all these different concepts
that I look out for. So what you just
need to do is go through the channel.
You will see the video on order block
liquidity imbalance boss and the rest.
Go ahead watch them so that you will
understand what each of these concepts
what they do and how you can also apply
them in your trading. I also have my VIP
group where you can also get your
classes, get to understand all these
things properly and also have the mind
to tread them. It's not about knowing
all these technical aspects. You also
need to work on the psychological aspect
by having the mind to trade this killing
the fear. So what you just need to do is
message me on WhatsApp. My WhatsApp
number is in the description. So just
click the link there, message me and get
access to the VIP book by picking the
particular package you need. We have the
monthly group, the yearly and the
lifetime. So you can pick the one you
can afford and get access to the